1389 NE Alex Way, Apt# 224 Hillsboro, OR – 97124

## TEJDEEP KAUTHARAM

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejdeepkautharam

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer Engineering (Computer Systems) graduate student with two years of professional experience and three months of internship experience in software development looking for full time opportunity. Core Competencies include:

Proficient in C++ and Java

Good OOP design

• Sound knowledge of algorithms and data structures

• Familiar with agile methodologies and SDLC

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Engineering (Computer Systems)

Aug 2014 - May 2016

Email: tejdeep.kautharam@intel.com

Mobile: (612)-669-6905

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ.

ug 2014 – May 201

**Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication** 

CGPA: 3.7

**CGPA: 3.87** 

Pondicherry University, Pondicherry, India

Aug 2008 - May 2012

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages** C, C++, C#, SQL, Java, Python.

Web Technologies HTML5, CSS3, ASP.NET MVC5, ADO.NET, XML, OWL, PHP, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJS.

**Operating Systems** LINUX, Windows XP/7/8.

Tools Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Protégé, Eclipse, Matlab, Visual Studio, GIT, MS Office.

Databases HDFS, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server 2008/10.

## **GRADUATE COURSEWORK**

Big Data Computing, Information Retrieval Mining and Integration, Distributed Database Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Distributed multi-processor OS, Distributed Software Development, Data Mining, Computer Systems (Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Computer Networks), communication networks.

### **GRADUATE PROJECTS**

# Spatial Spark - Geospatial Operations on Distributed Data

Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

- Designed and developed an application to implement Geo Spatial operations like Closest and Farthest Pair, Convex Hull, Geometric Union and Spatial Join using OOP concepts in Java on a distributed processing framework Apache Spark.
- Implemented Range partition, Round Robin partition, Parallel Join and Parallel Sort in Python using multi-threading concepts on the data stored in PostgreSQL.

## **Optical Character Recognition (OCR)**

Nov 2015 – Dec 2015

• Extracted text from image sources by designing and implementing Multi Class Perceptron Classifier and MIRA classifier using Python. Trained and tested these classifiers on set of scanned handwritten digit images.

# **Search Engine Implementation**

Jan 2015 - Apr 2015

- Developed the Vector Space Model using just TF/IDF weights to rank the documents in JAVA using LUCENE indexer.
- Developed the Authorities/Hub and Page Rank computation in JAVA on 25054 pages corpus and displayed matched results.
- Developed the clustering of results using K-means algorithm obtained on the top N results using TF/IDF.

### **Hotel Booking System**

Feb 2015 - Apr 2015

- Developed a Hotel booking system in C# by using multi-threading concepts that handles multiple booking transactions.
- Developed SOAP and RESTful location based services in C# and developed a 3-tier ASP. Net website which offers these services.

### Message Passing in Client Server Application

Sep 2014 - Dec 2014

- Developed non-preemptive scheduler in C on Linux by developing queues and Thread Controlled Blocks (TCB).
- Developed semaphore's routines in C and used them to achieve synchronization among multiple threads.
- Developed network API's to send and receive data from local/remote ports in a distributed OS environment.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer, Intel Corporation, Hillsboro, OR, USA.

### **Statistical Process Control (SPC)**

Jun 2016 -Present

• Developing Process Control Review System in C# for Statistical Process Control ASP.NET MVC5 web application.

Software Developer Intern, Intel Corporation, Santa Clara, CA, USA.

# Camera Module Simulator (CMS)

May 2015 -Dec 2015

- Developed command line utility in C++ for CMS that generates configuration files based on the command line parameters.
- Developed website for CMS and automated CMS input parameter generation using PHP and JavaScript.

Assistant System Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, India.

## Nielsen Answers Portal (https://nielseninreview.nielsen.com)

Aug 2012 -Jun 2014

• Designed and developed core business modules in C# and developed converters that converts raw sales data given by retail stores into suitable file formats and loads them into relational database using SQL Bulk loading utilities.